Guide to the IBT COVID-19 Response Collection, 2020 IBT0093
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT COVID-19 Response Collection
April 9, 2020-October 1, 2020
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0093
204 digital object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 2 series: International Brotherhood of Teamsters websites and Teamsters Locals and Affiliates websites.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was harvested and archived through Archive-It and Social Feed Manager
Biographical / Historical
On March 13, 2020, President Donald Trump declared a national emergency in response to the growing number of COVID-19 cases nationwide. Members of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters and the many Teamsters' affiliates and locals are employed in so-called "essential" services; nurses, grocery store clerks, police officers, delivery drivers, airline workers, and warehouse employees. This meant that, at a time when most of the country was at home, Teamsters' members were going to work to perform jobs that the rest of country depended on to run. This file was started in an effort to document and identify for future researchers how the IBT and the various Teamsters affiliates and locals have been communicating with and assisting their members in safely performing these duties.
Scope and Contents
This collection is compiled by a librarian from various IBT and Teamsters' local web-based sources. The list provides a guide for researchers to find all identified tweets and webpages addressing COVID-19 and the Teamsters' unions responses to either the pandemic or the quarantine.
COVID-19 (Disease); Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 21st century; Safety of workers
- Teamsters Twitter Handle Search, Posted to Twitter between March 16 and October 15, 2020; Series 1; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; Teamsters Local 320. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 320; Teamsters Local 2010. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 2010; Teamsters Local 783. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 783; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 237 (New York, N.Y.); Teamsters Local 396. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 396; Teamsters Local 399. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 399; Teamsters Local 988. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 988; Teamsters Local 117 (Tukwila, Wash.). International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 117 (Tukwila, Wash.); Teamsters Local 230. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 230; Teamsters Local 25. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 25; Teamsters Local 350. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 350; Teamsters Local 533. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 533; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Warehouse and Distribution Workers Local 688; Teamsters Local 727. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 727; Teamsters Local 822. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Local 822
  - Teamsters' COVID-19 Tweetset, Series 1
    Scope and Contents
    This material is available through Tweetset, GW Libraries' search interface for navigating archived tweets. The hashtags associated with the Teamsters' experience and response to the COVID-19 pandemic and quarantine have already been identified. They are listed here with the count of tweets containing each hashtag.
    Bendthecurve 143 tweets, CARESAct 40 tweets, CouncilsNotCOVID 25 tweets, coronavirus 950 tweets, CoronavirusPandemic 423 tweets, COVID 723 tweets, Covid19 302 tweets, Covid_19 101 tweets, COVID-19 77 tweets, COVID19 176 tweets, COVID19US 4 tweets, COVIDfrontlines 1 tweet, essential 56 tweets, EssentialAndExcluded 177 tweets, essentialworkers, EssentialWorker, FlattenTheCurve, frontline, FrontlineHeroes, HEROES, HEROESAct, HeroesNeedMasks, HiddenHeroes, MaskUpNV, MaskUpMN, NewYorkHERO, paidsickleave, PaidSickLeave, pandemic, PPE, ProtectHealthcareWorkers, ProtectNYHeroes, ProtectWorkers, StayHealthy, StaySafe
- Teamsters Web Archives, Harvested from the web between April 9, 2020 and October 30, 2020; Series 2
  This series is derived from multiple websites associated with the International Brotherhood of Teamsters as well as Teamsters locals that were harvested and preserved through the Internet Archive's Wayback Machine. Some links described in the item records may not be found in GW's instance of the captured website.
  - Public Service Division Secures Large Supply of PPE for Local 700 Members, 28 April 2020; Series 2
    Article about how the international helped Local 700 secure PPE.
  - Episode 195: Coronavirus Update #10, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    A coronavirus specific episode of the Teamster Nation Podcast
  - COVID-19 News Updates for May 18, 2020, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Collection of outside news sources about the coronavirus.
  - Teamster Hidden Heroes, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Photographs of Teamster members wearing masks while at various jobs.
  - COVID-19 Outbreak Resources, 27 April 2020; Series 2
    Resources compiled on April 27, 2020
  - Healthcare Workers Fact Sheet, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Teamster Health Care workers provide information for the Teamsters about the COVID outbreak and what is known about it.
  - Latest News, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Tiles with different news stories from different outside sources that discuss how the coronavirus pandemic impacts workers and worker rights and protection, including struggling to access PPE and labor conditions for nurses.
  - Longtime Local 727 Member Howard Switalla Volunteers to Assist in New York during Coronavirus Pandemic, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    An article from Local 727 about a long time Teamster going to New York City to help out admist the Coronavirus pandemic.
  - Teamsters say Final Pension Bill Must Include Multiemployer Pension Partition, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    A press release about legislation created as COVID-19 relief that concerned pension plans and the stimulus check.
  - Republic Services Workers Demand PPE and Improved Workplace Conditions Amid COVID-19 Pandemic, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    News about workers demands for a safer work environment admist COVID-19
  - COVID-19 News Updates for May 19, 2020, 12 May 2020; Series 2
  - Teamsters Homepage, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Teamsters homepage with mentions of nurses organizing in Michigan and workers in Georgia fighting to get PPE.
  - Public Sector Jobs At Risk Due to Senate Inaction, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Article about the economic impacts of COVID-19.
  - Teamster Union Lauds CARES Act Relief for YRCW workers, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    Article about the CARES act and its impact on freight drivers.
  - Women's Conference Webinars, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    Information about how the women's conference is adjusting and offering resources to its members.
  - Teamsters Hidden Heroes, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    A video tribute to teamsters who are essential workers throughout the pandemic.
  - California Elected Officials Join Striking Essential Workers In Caravan for Justice Through Los Angeles Wholesale Produce Market., 10 July 2020; Series 2
    A press release about a strike action in Los Angeles.
  - Risk and race concerns fuel ongoing debate around hazard pay during pandemic, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    A link to an outside source called Deep Dive about sanitation workers and racial dynamics.
  - COVID-19 News Updates for July 7, 2020, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    A round up of outside news sources from July about COVID-19.
  - Public Services "Member Town Hall" June 25 Webinar Recording, 11 July 2020; Series 2
    A webinar by the teamsters about how to stay "safe and sane."
  - COVID-19 Outbreak Resources, 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Message acknowledging the pandemic and the effects it will have on workers, with links to resources
  - Teamsters Local 331, 20 July 2020; Series 2
    Newsletter screenshot about LabCorp antibody testing
  - COVID-19 Statement 03-23-20, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Press release on COVID-19 from Secretary-Treasurer, Shannon R. George
  - Support Hazard Pay for Essential Public Sector Workers, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin encouraging readers to contact representatives so public sector workers can receive hazard pay during the pandemic
  - Update, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin with an update on pay freezes and PPEs
  - Union Meetings Postponed, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin announcing the postponement of union meetings due to coronavirus pandemic
  - Washington Teamsters Welfare Trust Memorandum on COVID-19 Actions Taken So Far, 25 March 2020; Series 2
    Memo discussing actions taken so far by the Washington Teamsters Welfare Trust regarding COVID-19 such as coverage extension, telehealth and virtual care, and testing.
  - How To Apply for Unemployment Benefits in Washington State, 17 March 2020; Series 2
    Flyer listing steps to applying for unemployment benefits in Washington State
  - Complete Listing of Essential Industries, 23 March 2020; Series 2
    List of industries and types of jobs that would be considered "essential" during COVID-19 pandemic
  - City of Seattle and State of Washington Resources for Workers Impacted by the COVID-19 Pandemic, No Date; Series 2
    List of resources specifically for Seattle and Washington State workers in response to COVID-19 pandemic
  - CARES Act (complete document), 27 March 2020; Series 2
    The complete CARES Act document to provide emergency assistance to individuals, families, and businesses affected by the 2020 coronavirus pandemic
  - Teamsters Local 174 Rejects Productivity Standards During COVID-19 Pandemic, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Article discussing demands for employers to value employee safety over productivity during COVID-19
  - April 9, 2020 General Membership and Initiates Meeting Canceled, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    A meeting cancelation announcement due to the "Stay Home, Stay Healthy" order for COVID-19 in Washington State
  - Members in Action: Waste Management Seattle Drivers Keep Working, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Images of Local 174 members/Seattle Waste Management team working amidst the COVID-19 pandemic
  - Re: Liability Waivers, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Response to contracters in Washington State requiring employees to sign liability waivers amidst the COVID-19 pandemic
  - COVID-19 Information on Unemployment and Paid Leave, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Federal and Washington State-specific resources for unemployment and paid leave
  - Families First Coronavirus Response Act: Employee Paid Leave Rights, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Document explaining the Families First Coronavirus Response Act
  - UPS Western Region Supplemental Leaders Led by Union Chairman Andy Marshall Reach Agreement Further Protecting Employees During COVID-19 Crisis, 30 April 2020; Series 2
  - Teamsters Local 174 - Essential Services Providers, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Letter discussing what employees could potentially qualify as "essential"
  - Washington Teamsters Welfare Trust Communication: COVID-19 Response Update, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Notice discussing the actions taken so far in response to COVID-19 such as family leave and testing
  - Washington Teamsters Welfare Trustees Vote to Extend Healthcare Coverage for Up to Three Months, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing vote to extend healthcare coverage for JC28 members
  - FMCSA Decision RE: Medical Exams for DOT Physicals, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing a waiver has been granted for DOT physicals for CDL and CLP holders after having difficulty due to contamination concers from COVID-19
  - Statewide "Stay Home" Order: Which Industries are Affected?, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Announcement regarding the Washington State governor's Stay at Home order during the COVID-19 pandemic
  - Teamsters Scholarship Update: Cavano Deadline Extended, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing the extension of the George Cavano scholarship deadline due to COVID-19
  - COVID-19 and UPS's Failed Handling of a Deadly Pandemic Vol. 1: Too Much Volume, Not Enough Hands, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin calling out UPS for for mistreatment of employees and working conditions during COVID-19 surge in business.
  - A Open Letter to Teamsters Local 174 Members from Secretary Treasurer Rick Hicks: "Thank you Governor Inslee for Taking Strong Action to Combat COVID-19 Pandemic.", 10 July 2020; Series 2
    A letter discussing the switch to more intensive measures against COVID-19 by Governor Inslee.
  - Teamsters Joint Council 28 President Rick Hicks Op-Ed: Trump Decision to Force Opening of Meat Processing Plants Will Lead to Deaths, 30 April 2020; Series 2
    Article warning against the reponing of meat processing plants due to over 100 workers already having contracted COVID
  - Teamsters Local 174 Members at Pozzi Bros. Transportation Unanimously Ratify New Agreement, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Announcing the first ratification via Zoom conference calling due to COVID-19 pandemic
  - Harstine Island Closed Until Further Notice due to COVID-19, 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Announcement of closure to Local 313's recrecational property, Harstine Island, due to COVID-19 restrictions
  - COVID-19 measures, 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Letter from local 370 president on safety measures taken due to COIVD-19
  - Notice: COVID-19 "Stay At Home Order", 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice supporting the stay at home order and announcing the continued suport of membership during COVID-19
  - Message from the Joint Council President, 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Letter from the joint council president regarding the different circumstances members may be enduring during the early statges of COVID-19
  - Important Notice: Coronavirus-related benefit improvements, 05 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing updates and information regaridng the benefits plan for members
  - Local 330 Member Bill Wolf Serving as Essential Worker During COVID-19 Pandemic, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Video link not archived
  - Notice: Cancellation of April 21, 2020 General Membership Meeting, 12 July 2020; Series 2
    Announcement regarding the cancelation of a meeting due to COVID-19
  - Governor Sununu Issues Emergency Order Re: Coronavirus, 09 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice from governor issuing five emergency orders
  - March 15, 2020 General Membership Meeting Canceled, 09 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice from Principal Officer Jeff Padellaro regarding a meeting cancellation due to COVID-19 (Coronavirus)
  - Employee Rights, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice discussing the paid sick and medical leave workers can receive from their employer
  - Attention Notice, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing the temporary closure of the office of Secretary /Treasurer Leonard Crouch due to COVID-19
  - Employment Security, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Employment Security
  - U.S. Department of Labor, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    U.S Department of Labor
  - Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Centers for Disease Control and Prevention
  - Port Truck Drivers Take Action, Demand Protections from COVID-19, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Port Truck Drivers Take Action, Demand Protections from COVID-19
  - COVID-19 News Updates - May 7, 2020, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    COVID-19 News Updates - May 7, 2020
  - Tell Kroger: Don't Cut Hazard Pay for Essential Workers, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Notice to announce Kroger is stopping the "Hero Bonus" after May 16
  - Teamsters Urge Treasury Department to Protect Miami Air International, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Article about Teamsters pressing for financial support for a charter airline Miami Air International that employs over 350 workers
  - New Essential Worker CDC Guidelines, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    New Essential Worker CDC Guidelines
  - Attention all Local 781 Members, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Attention all Local 781 Members
  - Illinois Teamsters Working -COVID-19, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Illinois Teamsters Working during COVID-19
  - Employee Rights COVID-19 Response Act, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Employee Rights COVID-19 Response Act
  - COVID-19 Resources, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Resources for COVID-19
  - Coronavirus Pandemic - Please Read, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Information regarding COVID-19
  - Unemployment Benefits COVID-19 Please Read, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Unemployment Benefits COVID-19 - Please Read
  - COVID-19 Important!, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    COVID-19 Information
  - COVID-19 News Updates - April 22, 2020, 28 April 2020; Series 2
    Long list of news updates and linked resources surrounding the virus
  - COVID-19 News Updates - April 23, 2020, 28 April 2020; Series 2
  - General Membership Meeting Cancelled, 28 April 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing the cancellation of membership meeting on May 11, 2020 due to COVID-19
  - UPS Agreement, No date; Series 2
    An agreement between UPS and its workers regarding paid leave and worker's rights due to COVID-19
  - COVID-19 News Updates for July 7, 2020, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    Updates and resources regarding safety precautions, paid leave, childcare, sanitation, and economic impact payments
  - Risk and race concerns fuel ongoing debate around hazard pay during global pandemic, 10 July 2020; Series 2
    Article discussing demands from sanitation workers for hazard pay during COVID
  - California essential workers join striking essential workers in caravan for justice through Los Angeles wholesale produce market, 09 July 2020; Series 2
    Frustrations and demands from Los Angeles essential workers towards the Wholesale Produce Market for better working conditions during COVID
  - Teamsters Local 638 32nd Annual event cancelled, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    Notice announcing the cancellation of the 32nd Annual event on July 25, 2020
  - Compassion in a Crisis, 24 July 2020; Series 2
    Teamsters fill the gaps with mutual aid and support to care for essential workers when employers fail.
  - During Coronavirus, Union Steps Up, 24 July 2020; Series 2
    Details on how Teamsters protected workers throughout the pandemic.
  - COVID-19 Outbreak Resources, 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Links to stories and resources for COVID-19 such as federal updates, statements from essential workers, and news stories
  - COVID-19 News Updates for May 15, 2020, 15 May 2020; Series 2
    List of updates and links to videos of President Trump or White House correspondants regarding COVID-19 pandemic
  - Local 839 Leaders Discuss COVID-19 Protections for Food Processing Workers (Video), 21 May 2020; Series 2
    Video discussing what protections would be put into place for essential workers in food processing industry
  - Teamster 727 Jewel-Osco Steward Ciprian Gorgan HIghlights Union's Fight for Better Working Conditions in Recent Tribune Article, 24 April 2020; Series 2
    Article about the demands towards Jewel-Osco and their essential workers during COVID-19
  - Teamsters Local 727 Benefit Fund Trustees Temporarily Extend Health and Welfare Coverage, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Bulletin explaining the extension of health and welfare coverage in response to COVID-19
  - During a National Crisis, Rolex Fails to Recognize its Essential Employees, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Comments on Rollex not paying their employees appropriately while they work during the pandemic
  - MV Transportation Division 422 Employees Left Out in the Cold While Others Remain Compensated, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Article commenting on the decision MV Transportation made to furlough some employees and not others
  - Park USA Makes Furloughed Teamsters Local 727 Members Whole, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Teamsters Local 727 applauds the recent efforts of valet parking company, Park USA.
  - Teamsters 727 Preserves Jobs, Wages and Benefits at One Parking During Stay at Home Order, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    One Parking agrees to preserve the wages for the thirty-five Local 727 member
  - Teamsters Local 727 Stands-Up Against Corporate Bully, Great Lakes Coca-Cola After the Company Tells Employee's to Remove Masks, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Article about Coca-Cola asking employees to remove their masks that had been provided to them by the Union.
  - Longtime Local 727 Member Howard Switalla Volunteers to Assist in New York during Coronavirus Pandemic, 12 May 2020; Series 2
    Numerous local members volunteer their experience as funeral directors, embalmers, livery drivers, and grave diggers during COVID-19 pandemic
  - Additional Film and Television Production Safety Guidelines Released by Multi-Union Task Force, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    Safety guidelines called "the Safe Way Forward" which outlines specific safety guidelines and includes guidance on mandatory testing, personal protective equipment (PPE), and department- specific procedures
  - Teamsters Work to Establish Safe Return-to-Work Policies for Motion Picture Division, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    Representatives of Teamsters along with IATSE, SAG-AFTRA, DGA and other producing entities and guilds have drafted a set of recommended return-to-work policies and safety protocols for motion pictures, television, and streaming productions during the COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Union Demands Safety Be Top Priority as CVS Rolls Out COVID-19 Testing Centers, 29 July 2020; Series 2
    After union pressures, CVS rolls out COVID-19 testing centers and will provide additional technician hours to all testing-center pharmacies
  - Tribune Engages in Bad Faith and Regressive Effects Bargaining Over Proposed Lay-Offs, 20 July 2020; Series 2
    Chicago Tribune implemented a "regressive" proposal to lay-off the two least senior drivers while also asking members to sign a confidentiality agreement
  - 727 Demands Bargaining Over Great Lakes Coca-Cola's Unjust Wellness Policy, 28 July 2020; Series 2
    Article mentioning multiple issues Local 727 has with Coco-Cola company and their mistreatment of employees during COVID-19
  - Great Lakes Coca-Cola Withholds Information From the Union Leading the Union to Ask What GLCC Has to Hide, 20 July 2020; Series 2
    Article explaining the issues the union has with Coco-Cola including Great Lakes Coca-Cola ending hazard pay after only a month with no notice to the Union.
  - Keeping our Members Safe!, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    An externally linked bulletin
  - In Case You Missed It, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    "Can unions surge in post-pandemic America."
  - May Day Strike at Amazon, Walmart, Fed Ex, Target, Instacart, and Whole Foods, 03 May 2020; Series 2
    Dangerous pandemic-caused working conditions at warehouses, in the "gig economy," and at big box stores are forcing tens of thousands of workers at six large firms – Amazon, Walmart, FedEx, Target, Instacart, Shipt, and Whole Foods – into a walkout during their lunch breaks on May 1.
  - Osha Inspectors Are Key to Reopening. Their Ranks Are at a 45-Year Low, 03 May 2020; Series 2